ANIRUDDH TIWARI



+91 9424669633



aniruddh8022@gmail.com



Ujjain, India



Aniruddh Tiwari



SKILLS

- Programing Language Python, C++, SQL.
- Database Management System MySQL, Firebase, SQlite
- Data Visualization Tools Tableau, Power BI.
- Front End Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- UX design Tools Figma, Axure, Adobe XD
- Machine Learning
- **Data Analytics**

EDUCATION

LOKMANYA TILAK VIDHYA VIHAR HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL UJJAIN, INDIA

Class X (2017) Class XII (2019)

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

Avantika University 2019-2023

PROFILE

My name is Aniruddh Tiwari, and I have been crazy about Machine Learning, Data Science, Data Analytics, and Data Visualization since I was in my 2nd year of academics. I built my first project in Machine Learning, Data Analytics, and Data Visualization in my 3rd year of academics. The feedback from those days from teachers worked wonders. I started learning more about Data Science, Machine learning, and Data Analytics and was amazed to see how little this is explored from a fresh perspective.

EXPERIENCE

UX DEVELOPER INTERN

CJ Digitals 1st June, 2022 - 30 August, 2022

DIGITAL MARKETING INTERN

Anar Business Community App 20th June, 2021 - 20 July, 2021

CERTIFICATION

- Introduction to Data Science (IBM)
- Python Basics for Data Science (IBM)

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Machine learning Projects

Diabetes Prediction:

Used Pima Indians Diabetes Database for diabetes production. Analyze at least 5-6 attributes of the dataset and Identify and implement any one Supervised Learning module. Identify software dependencies.

Tech Stack: Python, scikit learn, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib.

Rate of Intrest Prediction

For small banks and organizations that give loans, it becomes a tedious task to check the history of a loan taker and determine whether or not to give them a loan. This comes with an add-on task of deciding the different rates of interest for the various customers based on their history. Build a system that can analyze the previous loans taken by the customer and determine a loan of interest in case he/she are eligible to take another loan.

Tech Stack: Python, scikit learn, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib.

Data Analytics Projects:

Business Model:

Created a business model for the running business and identify their problems and create a 5-year business plan.

Coffee Chain Data Visualization Dashboard

Tech Stack: Tableau

Web Application Project

Animal Shelter Hifazat:

Sometimes while passing by on-road, we often find injured animals. We do want to help them but, we don't because we have our errands to run and also don't have much time to take them to the hospital or any shelter. To make this, feasible our website has an SOS application, so if you find an injured animal, the user can share his/her location with nearby shelters or NGOs so that they can come and help the animal around. Also, if you want to adopt a pet or donate money to support any NGOs or shelters, you can do it from our website Users will have to fill out a form for the adoption and the donation. The website will make sure to send your applications around and make proper use of your contribution. The user can also buy accessories and food products for their pet from the website

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL.

Data Base Management System: Mysql

Desktop Application

Animal Shelter Management System:

Being unable to manage records for adoption, rescued animals, animals are available for adoption, adopted animals, and total animals present in the shelter. This caused chaos in maintaining the record health and calculating donation amounts, and rescue operations for the animals.

Tech Stack: Qt c++, Qt Design, SQL Data Base Management System: SQLite

Android Mobile Application

Help Us:

Design and develop an android mobile application that will help to manage the wastage of food and fill the gaps between NGOs and Donors to help the needy.

Tech Stack: Android Studio, XML, Java Data Base Management System: Firebase

RESPONSIBILITY

- Avantika Drama Club Head
- Avantika Designeering Series Content Writer

INTEREST

- Acting
- Writing
- Story telling
- Problem Solving
- Travelling
- Reading